vbulletin.net 2012-05-10

# vBulletin Privacy Policy

We are committed to safeguarding your privacy online. This Privacy Policy applies to your information that we collect and receive on and through this Site; it does not apply to practices of businesses that we do not own or control or people we do not employ.

At no time will we sell or otherwise distribute your information or your personally-identifiable data without your permission. You can visit this Site without revealing who you are or providing any personal information about yourself.

By using this Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please read the following Privacy Policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you use this Site and its services. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices.

This Site contains links to other websites. These include links to websites that we think may be of interest to you. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

## Browsing this Site

If you browse through this Site without entering any personal data, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally and cannot be linked back to you unless you decide to identify yourself. If you are only browsing, we collect the following information: IP address, the type of browser and operating system used to access this Site, the date and time you access this Site, the pages you visit (click-through), and if you linked to this Site from another website, the address of that website as well as additional information related to your visit. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with this Site’s server, and to administer this Site.

## Information Collected

We collect the email addresses of consumers who communicate with us via email. We also collect information provided to us by consumers who purchase our software products, vBulletin Forum and vBulletin Suite, or services (collectively, “Purchase Information”). Collected Purchase Information includes the following: name, address, email address, telephone number and country. We do not collect credit card information or other sensitive financial information for orders placed online.

Other than wire transfer purchases, which we process directly, all financial transactions on this Site are processed on our behalf by PayPal or WorldPay. For information regarding the privacy policies of those companies, please refer to the following:

<http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside>  
[http://www.rbsworldpay.com/about_us/index.php?page=privacy&c=UK](http://www.rbsworldpay.com/about_us/index.php?page=privacy&c=UK)

If you request remote support services, such as technical support or software installation or upgrades, we may collect certain information required to fulfill your request. Remote support services often require sharing required server access details, such as username or password information in order to allow remote access. This allows our customer support team to access your server or software control panel in order to diagnose a problem or complete an upgrade or installation. By taking advantage of these services, you give permission to us and our customer support team to log in to your website server or software control panel, which may contain personal information.

All electronic communications received, either via email to non-personal addresses such as sales@vbulletin.com and support@vbulletin.com, or via the online contact system, are logged and retained for a period from the date of receipt, until such time as information is no longer needed or required by law. Communications from existing Site customers are automatically linked to their respective customer account. Secure information (including usernames, passwords and server details) submitted via the professional installation worksheet, are deleted from the database 30 days after the installation has been completed, whichever is earlier.

All information provided by consumers in any of the above-listed ways or otherwise becomes the property of vBulletin Solutions, Inc. once received and may be used and disclosed as permitted by this Privacy Policy. We share your personal information with our affiliated companies in order to identify products or services in which you may have interest, to improve Site user experience and generally to engage in market research and for other internal business purposes. We may also aggregate your personal information with others’ information and prepare reports on Site usage, purchase history or other factors for sale or distribution to others. Those reports are aggregated and include no personally-identifying information.

We may use your personal information to send you email communications regarding products or services offered by us or by third parties with whom we have relationships in which we think you may be interested.

We do not share, sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties for unknown reasons.

You may at any time choose not to receive promotional emails from us by changing the setting in your customer account or by contacting us at sales@vbulletin.com. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may continue to contact you for the purpose of communicating information relating to this Site, as well as to facilitate, complete, or confirm any transaction that you may enter into or responding to your inquiry or request.

If you prefer for us not to provide your name and email or postal address to third parties for direct marketing purposes, please contact us at sales@vbulletin.com.

## Cookies

We may place "cookies" on your personal computer. "Cookies" are small identifiers sent from a website server and stored on your computer’s hard drive, similar to a license plate, that help us to recognize you if you visit this Site again. Also, this Site uses cookies to track how you found this Site. Cookies are not designed to be used to get data from your hard drive, your email or any other personal data about you. To protect your privacy, we do not use cookies to store or transmit any personal information about you on the Internet. You can reject cookies by changing your browser settings, but please be aware that if you reject our cookies it is possible that some Site pages may not properly load, your access to certain information might be denied or you might have to enter information about yourself more than once.

## Security

This Site has reasonable security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

## Third Party Advertising 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements when you visit this Site. These companies use non-personally identifiable information regarding your visit to this Site and other websites, such as the user IP address, pages viewed, date and time of your visit, and number of times you have viewed an advertisement (but not your name, address, or other personal information), to serve advertisements to you on this Site and other websites that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to this Site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique cookie on your Internet browser. 

In addition, we use clear GIFs or pixel tags to help manage our online advertising. These clear GIFs enable our advertisement serving company to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits this Site. This allows us to learn which banner advertisements bring users to this Site. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable.

To learn more about these practices and your choices about not having this information used by these companies please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

## Contacting this Site

Please be aware that we may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. If we do, we will update this Privacy Policy on this Site, so be sure to check back here frequently. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you may contact us at sales@vbulletin.com.

vBulletin.com

Revised: 06/16/2010
